Mind over mayhem.
Birds of Prey (and the Fantabulous Emancipation of One Harley
Quinn) is a action, crime film directed by Cathy Yan.
Harley Quinn joins forces with a singer, an assassin and a police detective to help a young girl
who had a hit placed on her after she stole a rare diamond from a crime lord.
Harley Quinn, played by Margot Robbie.
Renee Montoya, played by Rosie Perez.
Helena Bertinelli / Huntress, played by Mary Elizabeth Winstead.
Dinah Lance / Black Canary, played by Jurnee Smollett.
Roman Sionis, played by Ewan McGregor.
Cassandra Cain, played by Ella Jay Basco.
Birds of Prey (and the Fantabulous Emancipation of One Harley Quinn) (also known as Harley Quinn: Birds of Prey, or
simply Birds of Prey) is a 2020 American superhero film based on the DC Comics team the Birds of Prey.
Directed by Cathy Yan and written by Christina Hodson, it is the eighth installment in the DC
Extended Universe (DCEU) and serves as a spin-off and sequel to Suicide Squad (2016).
The film stars Margot Robbie as Harley Quinn alongside Mary Elizabeth Winstead, Jurnee
Smollett-Bell, Rosie Perez, Chris Messina, Ella Jay Basco, Ali Wong, and Ewan McGregor.
It follows Harley Quinn, who, after breaking up with the Joker, is threatened by Gotham City crime lord Roman Sionis and joins
forces with Helena Bertinelli, Dinah Lance, and Renee Montoya (who form the Birds of Prey) to save Cassandra Cain.
Robbie, who also served as producer, pitched the
idea for Birds of Prey to Warner Bros.
The film was announced in May 2016, with Hodson being hired to write the script
that November, followed by Yan signing on to direct in April 2018.
The majority of the cast and crew were confirmed by December 2018.
Principal photography lasted from January to April 2019 in Downtown Los Angeles,
parts of the Los Angeles Arts District, and soundstages at Warner Bros.
Studios in Burbank, California.
Additional filming took place in September 2019.
Birds of Prey had its world premiere in Mexico City on January 25, 2020, and was released
in the United States in IMAX, Dolby Cinema, ScreenX and 4DX on February 7.
The film received generally positive reviews from critics, but was a box-office disappointment, grossing
$205.5 million worldwide, falling short of its reported break-even point of $250–300 million.
The film explores themes of police, pickpocket, chase, psychopath, superhero.